Andriy Kotko

Frontend developer

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/kotkoa Github: https://github.com/Kotkoa Telegram: https://t.me/Kotkoa +34 647 18 54 06

kotkoa@gmail.com

★ English: Advanced (C1)

Valencia Alicante Pego

Summary

Frontend Developer with 6 years of experience, I specialize in creating web applications, focusing on fintech, social media, the gig economy, and securities. My tech stack: React, TypeScript, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, Node.js, Jest, Tailwind. I'm skilled in managing and testing API requests, aiming to contribute to improving design systems and application UI. I'm an empathetic person who is comfortable with changes, a speedy learner, and has a can-do, roll-up-your-sleeves attitude.

Technical Skills

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Typescript, Vite, Next.js, Apollo graphQl, Rest API, Jotai, Mobx, react-context, Redux, CSS modules, Tailwind, Material-UI, Radix-UI, Jest, Cypress, Yup-validation, Figma, Storybook, React Drag-n-Drop, TV Lightweight Charts, JSON Forms, Github, Gitlab, CI/CD practices, ESLint, Prettier

Experience

From June 2022 to February 2024

Senior Frontend developer

Human Capital Exchange (HCX), Los Angeles - (Remote)

I've joined the <a href="https://example.com/h

- Streamlined account setup with multi-form flows for different users, integrating JSON Forms, Yup validation, and Apollo GraphQL, improving form submission efficiency by 90% and user satisfaction by 7%.
- Enhanced API in partnership with backend team, adding features and fixing bugs, which boosted server performance by 20% and accelerated feature deployment by 25%.
- Streamlined the system by removing 3 blockchain libraries, shifting to bank transactions, and introducing debit/credit card and bank account features, reducing operation costs by 30%.
- Implemented legal signing by DocuSign for in-app application signings, and user ID verification by integrating Onfido to authenticate documents and data, to meet KYC regulations and pass legal checking.
- Optimized 6+ key content pages for SEQ objectives, which improved onlinesearch-ranking accuracy by 63%
- Integrated Jest and Cypress with CI/CD for automated user flow testing, reducing manual QA time by 25%.
- Created 48 reusable UI components, cutting development time by 34% for future projects.
- Enhanced Material-UI global theme, streamlining common styles to save 68 workdays on component creation and saving the company 8000\$.

Technologies Used: React, Jotai, Context, Material-UI, Figma, Apollo GraphQL, React Native, JSON Forms, DnD kit, TV Chart Library, Nx Monorepo, Next.js, WordPress, Jest, Cypress, React Native, Go, Python

From April 2021 to June 2022

UI Developer

Yara International , Singapore - (Remote)

Hired to enhance the usability and accessibility of <u>Yara International's</u> design system, focusing on creating new components and refactoring existing ones. This role required technical proficiency and design skills to develop components within the company's design system. The project with NxMonorepo, consolidates web (React) and mobile (React Native) libraries for developers.

- Enriched a React library with over 10 new components, and refactored 100% existing ones
- Improved accessibility by conducting audits and enhancements, aligning components with global standards, and boosting compliance by 44%.
- Updating design system documentation from 5 versions to Storybook@7, optimizing infrastructure, and overhauling documentation for improved clarity and utility for 2 month
- Created a novel token system, enhancing design-to-code efficiency by 32%, leading to smoother design adoption and uniformity across projects.
- Team Collaboration: Worked closely with designers to refine and implement component designs, discussing the overall look of the Storybook theme.
- Elevated QA with strict code testing, achieving 98.1% reliability on browsers and devices.

Technologies Used: React.js, TypeScript, Jest, Storybook, Figma, Design System Library, npm, Radix-Ui, Markdown, React SPA, Girthub, React Native

Experience

From January 2020 to March 2021

Frontend developer

Root Name System (RNS), Cryptic Labs , Singapore, Los Angeles - (Remote)

I joined an international tech team as a frontend developer to develop from scratch and maintain their innovative digital identity platform, rns.id (Root Name System). The project aimed to develop an application by issuance of digital IDs of digital residence islands of Palau. My role was on optimizing and developing web applications, integrating new features of Document verifications, BE Api, TypeScript migration, and Jest test coverage. A key part of my responsibilities included fast-forwarding landing page creation and emails to meet marketing team goals.

- Spearheaded the creation of 3 React-based landing pages, 2 web apps, and 35 email HTML templates for user subscriptions, enhancing user engagement.
- Transformed MaterialUI concepts into styled-components, boosting UI flexibility and reducing load time.
- Simplified codebase by transitioning from Redux, Redux-toolkit to MobX, reducing boilerplate by 40% and enhancing maintainability.
- Launched a multi-site experience (SSR and SPA) within one web application, facilitating the independent development of 2 websites while maintaining uniform control, increasing operational efficiency by 25%.
- Integrated internationalization using i18n, expanding market reach by enabling content localization for 12 new languages, which led to a 28% increase in global user engagement.

Technologies Used: React, Next.js, Tailwind, Redux, Mobx, SASS, Mobx, Python, Blockchain, S3

From March 2018 to January 2020 Freelance WebDeveloper

Kotkoa Ukraine

I was acting as a FE developer of a web application for my business and SEO optimization. The applications were built with WordPress CMS and ready-to-use design system frameworks and were designed to be responsive and accessible across various devices.

- Creating HTML markup templates and Updating and modifying existing CSS code
- Maintainance HTML content daily and uploading content on different platforms
- Web Applications Graphic Design and Development
- Website Graphic Design and Development

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, WordPress, Joomla, GoogleAnalitycs, Seo-optimisation,

Education

2004 - Bachelor's degree: Precision Mechanics Instruments Engineer

Technical State University Sevastopol, Ukraine

2020 - Student: Javascript Developer

Self-taught frontend developer using free open bits of knowledge.